Edwin T. Dahlberg Papers
Edwin T. Dahlberg Papers
1921-1956
Dahlberg, Edwin T. (Edwin Theodore), 1892-1986.
14 linear ft.
Papers of the Baptist minister, ordained in 1918; pacifist. Correspondence, incoming and outgoing, primarily to or from members of the First Baptist Church in Syracuse; sermons; printed material, including church bulletins and newsletters, clippings; and photographs.
148923
Biographical History
The Reverend Edwin Theodore Dahlberg (1892-1986) was an American Baptist minister. Born in Minnesota, he attended the University of Minnesota from which he graduated with a B. D. in 1914. He continued his training at Rochester Theological Seminary from which he graduated in 1917. He was ordained a Baptist minister in 1918. Later, in 1939 he received a D. D. from Keuka College.
His first parish was the First Church in Potsdam, New York where he served from 1918-1921. He then took over the ministry at the Naple Street Church in Buffalo, New York from 1921-1931. From there he moved to the First Baptist Church in St. Paul, Minnesota where he worked from 1931-1939. From 1939-1950 he served as the pastor of the First Baptist Church of Syracuse, New York. In 1950 he was invited to assume the ministry of the Delmar Baptist Church in St. Louis, Missouri. Despite his sometimes-controversial pacifism, Dahlberg was elected President of the American Baptist Churches (1946-1947) and later served as President of the National Council of Churches (1957-1960). He was also a member of the Board of Trustees of Colgate-Rochester Divinity School and of Shurtleff College, and was invited to guest preach at locations across the country.
Throughout his career Reverend Dahlberg was known for his strong efforts for social justice and peacemaking. He was a pacifist and conscientious objector during World War I and an early leader of the Fellowship of Reconciliation, and his efforts supporting the Civil Rights movement, opposing the Vietnam War, and promoting nuclear disarmament, led to the creation of the Edwin T. Dahlberg Peace Award by American Baptists in 1964. Awarded at the annual (now biennial) meeting of the denomination, recipients of the award have included civil rights activist Martin Luther King, Jr. (1964), President Jimmy Carter for his work on the Israel-Egypt Peace Treaty (1979), founder of Pastors for Peace Lucius Walker (1989), and Marian Wright Edelman, African-American lawyer and founder of the Children’s Defense Fund (1997).
Reverend Dahlberg wrote a few books and many articles published in such religious magazines as The Baptist Leader, The New Century Leader, The Watch-Examiner, The Christian Evangelist, Consolation, and Topic. Many pamphlets of his sermons have been published by The American Baptist Home Mission Society. A biography of him, Edwin T. Dahlberg: Pastor, Peacemaker, Prophet (Judson Press: Valley Forge, PA), was published by his son Keith in 1998.
[Portions of this biographical sketch adapted from: Westmoreland-White, Michael L. "Dahlberg Award Winners". Levellers. 10 Apr 2008 http://levellers.wordpress.com/dahlberg-award-winners.]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Edwin T. Dahlberg Papers consists of correspondence (incoming, outgoing, and family), subject files, published materials, and sermons.
Incoming correspondence consists of letters sent to Mr. Dahlberg by various organizations to which he belonged and from individuals, most of whom were members of the First Baptist Church in Syracuse. Most of the letters were written by service men and women who belonged to the First Baptist Church. These letters are dated 1944 - 1945.
Outgoing correspondence consists of the church news letters sent by Reverend Dahlberg to his parishioners of the Maple Street Church in Buffalo, and the. First Baptist Church in Syracuse. and to the service men and women of his church. There are a few letters addressed to individuals.
Family correspondence contains incoming letters written to him by his family.
Subject files consists of various kinds of material including study materials, copies of various church bulletins, pamphlets, newspaper clippings, notes, calling cards, and photographs.
Published materials consists of two (2) published pamphlets by other ministers and a pamphlet published by The American Baptist Home Mission Society.
Sermons contains copies of sermons written and delivered by Reverend Dahlberg. They are arranged alphabetically by the title of the sermon.
Arrangement of the Collection
Incoming correspondence is arranged in alphabetical order by the last name of the sender or the name of the organization. Outgoing correspondence is arranged chronologically. Family correspondence is arranged alphabetically by the name of the sender. Subject files are arranged alphabetically by topic. Published material and sermons are arranged alphabetically by title.
Subject and Genre Headings
Church and clergy; Activism and social reform; Dahlberg, Edwin T. (Edwin Theodore), 1892-1986 -- Archives.; First Baptist Church (Syracuse, N.Y.); Baptists -- Clergy.; Clergy -- United States.; Pacifism -- Religious aspects -- Baptists.; Pacifists -- United States.; Sermons, American.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Photographs.; Sermons.; Clergy.; Pacifists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Incoming correspondence
  - A (Box 1)
  - Agne, Richard R. (Box 1)
  - America-Israel Society (Box 1)
  - American Baptist Foreign Mission Society (Box 1)
  - Angle, Carleton (Box 1)
  - Ba-Bl (Box 1)
  - Bo-Bu (Box 1)
  - Beattie, Cecil A. (Box 1)
  - Blake, Lloyd & Shirley (Box 1)
  - Brown, Douglas A. (Box 1)
  - Burkett, May Thompson (Box 1)
  - Ca-Col (Box 1)
  - Com-Cr (Box 1)
  - Clow, Marian G. (Box 1)
  - Coddington, Walter A. (Box 1)
  - Collins, William B. (Box 1)
  - DePoer, J. Henry (Box 1)
  - Diets, Herb (Box 1)
  - E (Box 1)
  - Eldred, Eldon G. (Box 1)
  - F (Box 1)
  - Federal Council of the Churches of Christ (Box 1)
  - Fitch, Robert (Box 1)
  - Fosdick, Harry Emerson (Box 1)
  - Fuller, Neil G. (Box 1)
  - Gettman, Ted (Box 1)
  - Gilcher, Walter H. (Box 1)
  - Haynes, Ida E. (Box 1)
  - I (Box 1)
  - J (Box 1)
  - K (Box 2)
  - Klassi,Ed L. (Box 2)
  - Lee, George W. (Box 2)
  - Ma-Mon (Box 2)
  - Moo-Mu (Box 2)
  - Mellor, L. Robert (Box 2)
  - Morel, Charles S. (Box 2)
  - N (Box 2)
  - National Council of the Churches of Christ (Box 2)
  - Nauman, Harold P. (Box 2)
  - Northern Baptist Convention (Box 2)
  - O (Box 2)
  - P (Box 2)
  - Parce, Arthur M. (Box 2)
  - Parker, J. E. (Box 2)
  - Peck, Donald C. (Box 2)
  - Perrine, Robert A. (Box 2)
  - Phelps, Kenneth H. (Box 2)
  - Porter, Donald (Box 2)
  - Porter, Robert (Box 2)
  - R (Box 2)
  - Reussow, Gus and Shirley (Box 2)
  - S (Box 2)
  - Sanderson, Donald (Box 2)
  - Schroeder, John R. (Box 2)
  - Schweitzer, Albert (Box 2)
  - Scroxton, Richard R. (Box 2)
  - Shafer, Charles (Box 2)
  - Shearer, Lillian B. (Box 2)
  - Shinaman, Keith R. (Box 2)
  - Silliman, Melvin A. (Box 2)
  - Spencer, Charles (Box 2)
  - T (Box 3)
  - Tapper, Wayne U. (Box 3)
  - U (Box 3)
  - V (Box 3)
  - Van Bramer, Clara R. (Box 3)
  - Van Ness, A. W. (Box 3)
  - W (Box 3)
  - Watanabe, Frank (Box 3)
  - Williams, Rollin D. (Box 3)
  - World Council of Churches (Box 3)
  - Y (Box 3)
  - Z (Box 3)
  - Sender unknown (Box 3)
- Outgoing correspondence
  - 25 Apr 1923-15 Sep 1927 (Box 3)
  - 8 Dec 1938-26 Jan 1957 (Box 3)
  - Undated (Box 3)
  - Dr. Dahlberg to Service Man and Women (Box 3)
- Family correspondence
  - Incoming, A-Z (Box 3)
- Subject files
  - Conference On the Church and War-Study Materials (Box 3)
  - "The Baptist Voice" (Box 3)
  - "The Messenger" (Box 3)
  - "The Mizpah Messenger" First Baptist Church (Box 3)
  - "The First Baptist Outpost" numbers 1-18 (Box 3)
  - Various Church & Church Service Pamphlets (Box 3)
  - Introduction To "Book of Memoirs" of Delmar Baptist Church (Box 3)
  - "Mitzpah Messenger" newsletter (Box 23)
  - Newspaper Clippings About Service Men and Women (Box 3)
  - Notes About F.B.C. Service Men and Women (Box 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings About Baptists, Baptist Church, & Dahlberg (Box 3)
  - Notes About Parishioners (Box 3)
  - Calling Cards of Others (Box 3)
  - Pictures of Dahlberg and Family (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous oversize, World War II, pictures, letters, etc. (file card box) (Box 24)
- Published materials
  - "After Fifty Years" by Dr. Roland Knight (Sermon) (Box 3)
  - "Glasgow Cathedral: A Short History and Guide" by Rev. A. Nevile Davidson (Box 3)
  - "Looking Both Ways With the Indian" (Box 3)
- Sermons
  - "Aaron: the Praying Helper" (Box 4)
  - "The Absent Son" (Box 4)
  - "Absentee Pastor" (Box 4)
  - "The Abundant Life" (Box 4)
  - "Across the Lake" (Box 4)
  - "Adam, Eve, and the Atom" (Box 4)
  - Add Dahlberg, Hartford (2GB2/25/59) (Box 4)
  - "Airplane View of New Testament" (Box 4)
  - "The Aisle of God" (Box 4)
  - "All the City Was Stirred" (Box 4)
  - "Altars in the Dark" (Box 4)
  - "Amateurs Are Experts" (Box 4)
  - "America: Challenge To the Church" (Box 4)
  - "America For Christ" (Box 4)
  - "The American Baptist Educational Air Lift" (Box 4)
  - "American Catholicism" (Box 4)
  - "American Catholicism and Protestantism At the Well of Sychar" (Box 4)
  - "The American Indian and the Trail of Tears" (Box 4)
  - "The American Miracle" (Box 4)
  - "America's Ideals" (Box 4)
  - "America's Next President" (Box 4)
  - "America's Sea Walls" (Box 4)
  - "The Ancient of Days" (Box 4)
  - "The Ancient Landmark" (Box 4)
  - "And He Taught There" (Box 4)
  - "And the Holy Spirit" (Box 4)
  - "Another Chance After Death" (Box 4)
  - "Another Picture of Martha and Mary" (Box 4)
  - "Anxiety For All the Churches" (Box 4)
  - "Apostolic Anxiety For All the Churches" (Box 4)
  - "Apostolic Mileage" (Box 4)
  - "Appeal To the Summit" (Box 4)
  - "Apples of Gold" (Box 4)
  - "Are All Religions Equally Good?" (Box 4)
  - "Are We Converted Men?" (Box 4)
  - "Are We Too Near To Jesus?" (Box 4)
  - "Are You Able?" (Box 4)
  - "Are You a Christian?" (Box 4)
  - "The Aroma of Christ" (Box 4)
  - "As a Thief In the Night" (Box 4)
  - "As It Is In Heaven" (Box 4)
  - "As Love Knows How" (Box 4)
  - "At the Right Hand of God" (Box 4)
  - "The Attributes of God" (Box 4)
  - "Attempting Great Things For God" (Box 4)
  - "The Authority and Urgency of the Christian Mission" (Box 4)
  - "Authority In Religion" (Box 4)
  - "The Awakened Church" (Box 4)
  - "Bad Theology-Triumphant Faith" (Box 4)
  - "Bag Pipers of the Border Clans" (Box 4)
  - "Banditry an the Ecumenical Road" (Box 4)
  - "The Baptism" (Box 4)
  - "The Baptismal Experiences of Life" (Box 4)
  - "Baptism and the Lord's Supper" (Box 4)
  - "The Baptist Church: Defender of Soul Liberty" (Box 4)
  - "The Baptist Jubilee Advance" (Box 4)
  - "Baptist Progress" (Box 4)
  - "Baptists and Their History" (Box 4)
  - "Baptists and the State" (Box 4)
  - "The Baptist Witness in the Ecumenical Movement" (Box 4)
  - "Baptist World Alliance" (Box 4)
  - "Baptist World Congress Address" (Box 4)
  - "The Barnyard Sunday School" (Box 4)
  - "Battle For India" (Box 4)
  - "Bearer of the Bread" (Box 4)
  - "The Beautiful Gate" (Box 5)
  - "The Beauty and Union of the Church" (Box 5)
  - "The Beer Parade" (Box 5)
  - "Before the Evil Days Come" (Box 5)
  - "Before Jehovah's Awful Throne" (Box 5)
  - "The Beginnings of the Christian Church" (Box 5)
  - "The Beginning of the Gospel" (Box 5)
  - "Behold, This Dreamer" (Box 5)
  - "Belief and Achievement" (Box 5)
  - "Believing Everything-A Little" (Box 5)
  - "The Best Laugh of the Season" (Box 5)
  - "Th1 Bible and the Vatican" (Box 5)
  - "The Bible Comes Alive" (Box 5)
  - "The Bible in Education" (Box 5)
  - "The Bible Hath a Various Language" (Box 5)
  - "Biblical Concepts of Abundant Living" (Box 5)
  - "The Biblical in Preaching" (Box 5)
  - "The Birthday of the Church" (Box 5)
  - "The Bishop's Religion" (Box 5)
  - "Black Chimneys" (Box 5)
  - "Blessedness and Happiness" (Box 5)
  - "The Blind Man's Cane" (Box 5)
  - "The Bok Peace Plan" (Box 5)
  - "The Book of Breathings" (Box 5)
  - "The Book of Job" (Box 5)
  - 'The Book of Jonah" (Box 5)
  - "The Book of Revival" (Box 5)
  - "The Book to Live By" (Box 5)
  - "The Bootleggers' Religion" (Box 5)
  - "Born Anew" (Box 5)
  - "Bought With a Price" (Box 5)
  - "Boy Scouts in the Bible" (Box 5)
  - "Breaking Bread Together" (Box 5)
  - "Breaking Down Our Father's Altars" (Box 5)
  - "The Breaking of Bread" (Box 5)
  - "A Bridge Across the Centuries" (Box 5)
  - "Broken Sunshine" (Box 5)
  - "The Brotherhood of the Kingdom" (Box 5)
  - "Building a Tower" (Box 5)
  - "Building an Great Foundations" (Box 5)
  - "The Burden of the Valley of Vision" (Box 5)
  - "Business in Great Waters" (Box 5)
  - "Busy Here and There" (Box 5)
  - "Buy a Field!" (Box 5)
  - "Can Prayer Change the Mind of God?" (Box 5)
  - "Can Protestantism Unite?" (Box 5)
  - "Can We Achieve Universal Disarmament?" (Box 5)
  - "Can We Evangelize Evangelism?" (Box 5)
  - "Can We Have a United American Church" (Box 5)
  - "Can We Keep Up With Russia 7" (Box 5)
  - "Can You Meet an Emergency?" (Box 5)
  - "The Canadian Millennium" (Box 5)
  - "The Candle Maker" (Box 5)
  - "The Caravans of Abraham" (Box 5)
  - "Carried of God" (Box 5)
  - "A Catholic-Protestant Good Neighbor Policy" (Box 5)
  - "Cave Men" (Box 5)
  - "The Centuries and the Days" (Box 5)
  - "The Changing Conditions of Motherhood" (Box 5)
  - "Chapels of Silence" (Box 5)
  - "Character-What For?" (Box 5)
  - "The Chariots of Tutankhamen" (Box 5)
  - "The Child and the Multitude" (Box 5)
  - "The Child in the Box" (Box 5)
  - "The Choice of a Vocation" (Box 5)
  - "Christ and the Centurion" (Box 5)
  - "Christ and the Children" (Box 5)
  - "Christ and Communism" (Box 5)
  - "Christ and the Demons" (Box 5)
  - "Christ and Economics" (Box 5)
  - "Christ and the Jews" (Box 5)
  - "Christ and the Kingdom of God" (Box 5)
  - "Christ and the Publicans" (Box 5)
  - "Christ As Entrance" (Box 5)
  - "Christ Came Walking" (Box 5)
  - "Christ Cleansing the Temple" (Box 5)
  - "The Christ in Purple" (Box 5)
  - "Christ in the Ghetto" (Box 5)
  - "Christ in the Midst" (Box 5)
  - "The Christ of All Nations" (Box 5)
  - "Christ of Belial" (Box 5)
  - "The Christ of Power" (Box 5)
  - "Christ On Guard" (Box 5)
  - "Christ an the High Bridge" (Box 5)
  - "Christ or Barabbas?" (Box 5)
  - "Christ or Compromise?" (Box 6)
  - "Christ or Don Quixote?" (Box 6)
  - "Christ or Krishnamurti?" (Box 6)
  - "Christ Rides Into Jerusalem" (Box 6)
  - "Christ the Chief Cornerstone" (Box 6)
  - "Christ the Giver of Abundant Life" (Box 6)
  - "Christ the Hope of Our Calling" (Box 6)
  - "Christ the Hope of the Church" (Box 6)
  - "Christ the Hope of the World" (Box 6)
  - "Christ the Light of the World" (Box 6)
  - "Christ the Son" (Box 6)
  - "Christ the Son of Man" (Box 6)
  - "Christ the True Vine" (Box 6)
  - "The Christ We Proclaim" (Box 6)
  - "The Christ With the Keys" (Box 6)
  - "Christ's Baptismal Crisis" (Box 6)
  - "Christ's Body-Broken-Glorified" (Box 6)
  - "Christ's Competitors" (Box 6)
  - "Christ's Confession" (Box 6)
  - "Christ's Consciousness of Our Human Needs" (Box 6)
  - "Christ's Covered Wagons" (Box 6)
  - "Christ's Exceptions" (Box 6)
  - "Christ's Gospel For Civilized Men" (Box 6)
  - "Christ's Greatest Revival" (Box 6)
  - "Christ's Part in Education" (Box 6)
  - "Christ's Passion For an Education" (Box 6)
  - "Christ's Plan For the Planet" (Box 6)
  - "Christ's Spiritual Struggles" (Box 6)
  - "Christ's Teachings an Safety" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian and His Brethren" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian and His Church" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian and His God" or "Why Humanism?" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian and His Pleasures" or "Why Night Clubs" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian and the Fortune Teller" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian and the Humanist" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian-Attitude" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian Attitude Toward Sex" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian Belief in Man" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian Brotherhood of Man" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian Church in the Non-Christian World" (Box 6)
  - "A Christian Conscience in Highway Traffic" (Box 6)
  - "In Christian Education" (Box 6)
  - "Christian Elections" (Box 6)
  - "Christian Enlistment Week" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian Faith in a World Adrift" (Box 6)
  - "Christian Faith is Essential to Successful Family Life" (Box 6)
  - Christian Family Week Series (Box 6)
  - "Christian Friendship" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian Home" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian in the Modern World" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian International" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian Invasion of Personality" (Box 6)
  - "Christian Living at Its Best" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian Ministry" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian Patriot" (Box 6)
  - "A Christian Program of Peace" (Box 6)
  - "Christian Prayer" (Box 6)
  - "Christian Race Relations in America" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian Religion in the Rocket Age" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian State" (Box 6)
  - "Christian Systematics" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian Underground in Japan" (Box 6)
  - "Our Christian World Mission-A Two-Way Street" (Box 6)
  - "A Christian Youth Apostolate" (Box 6)
  - "Christian Youth's Swift Perfection" (Box 6)
  - "Christianity an International Force" (Box 6)
  - "Christianity: an Order or an Ideal?" (Box 6)
  - "Christianity and the Car Strike" (Box 6)
  - "Christianity: a Foot-note to History?" (Box 6)
  - "Christianity and the Non Christian Religions" (Box 6)
  - "Christianity As Rest" (Box 6)
  - "Christianity, in Action" (Box 6)
  - "Christianity on the Rough" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian's Book Shelf" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian's Book Table" (Box 6)
  - "Christians by Acclamation" (Box 6)
  - "Christians Coming!" (Box 6)
  - "Christians Courageous" (Box 6)
  - "Christians Cum Laude" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian's Daily Life" (Box 6)
  - "Christians' Faith in Immortality" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian's Impact on Public Opinion" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian's International Faith" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian's Library" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian's International Reparations" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian's Superior World" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian's Surplus" (Box 6)
  - "The Christian's Trophy" (Box 7)
  - "The Christian's Unfinished Work" (Box 7)
  - "Christians, What Cheer?" (Box 7)
  - "The Christmas Kingdom" (Box 7)
  - "Chundra Lela" (Box 7)
  - "The Church and the World" (Box 7)
  - "The Church in Politics" (Box 7)
  - "The Church in Prayer" (Box 7)
  - "The Church in the Wildwood" (Box 7)
  - "The Church: Is It For or Against Christ?" (Box 7)
  - "The Church: Its Ministry and Membership" (Box 7)
  - "The Church, Its Own Evangelist" (Box 7)
  - "The Church Member and the Eighteenth Amendment" (Box 7)
  - "The Church Member and the Missionary" (Box 7)
  - "Church of the Air" (Box 7)
  - "The Church of '61" (Box 7)
  - "The Church of the Future" (Box 7)
  - "Church Press For All" (Box 7)
  - "The Church Today" (Box 7)
  - "Church Unity and the Fullness of Christ" (Box 7)
  - "Church Work from the Pastor's Point of View" (Box 7)
  - "The Churches Come to Evanston" (Box 7)
  - "Churches in Communion" (Box 7)
  - "The Churches Met at Cleveland" (Box 7)
  - "The Churches, the Communists, and the Anti-Communists" (Box 7)
  - "Our Churches Future" (Box 7)
  - "The Churches Pentecostal Power" (Box 7)
  - "Citizenship: Keg Lined" (Box 7)
  - "The Clear Revelations of God" (Box 7)
  - "Clock of the Nations" (Box 7)
  - "Clouds Across the Sea" (Box 7)
  - "Coins or Compassion?" (Box 7)
  - "Cold Wars and Lukewarm Christianity" (Box 7)
  - "The College Student and His Home Church" (Box 7)
  - "Colonies of Heaven" (Box 7)
  - "Comic Opera Christians" (Box 7)
  - "The Coming Kingdom and the King Enthroned" (Box 7)
  - "The Command to Believe" (Box 7)
  - "The Commanding God" (Box 7)
  - "The Commission to Judas" (Box 7)
  - "Common Requirements of Uncommon-Lives" (Box 7)
  - "Common Sense Living" (Box 7)
  - "The Commonest Question About Prayer" (Box 7)
  - "The Communing God" (Box 7)
  - "Communism and the Clergy" (Box 7)
  - "Compassionate Christianity" (Box 7)
  - "The Compassionate God" (Box 7)
  - "Comprehending Christ" (Box 7)
  - "Compulsory Blessings" (Box 7)
  - "Condemnation of Salvation" (Box 7)
  - "Conditions of a Revival" (Box 7)
  - "Conditions of a National Revival"' (Box 7)
  - "Confessions of Christ" (Box 7)
  - "The Confession of Peter" (Box 7)
  - "The Congregation of the Mighty" (Box 7)
  - "The Congregation's Sermon" (Box 7)
  - "The Congress of Vienna" (Box 7)
  - "Consecrating Our Ability" (Box 7)
  - "Consider the Lilies" (Box 7)
  - "To Content the Multitude" (Box 7)
  - "Contrivance in Christ" (Box 7)
  - "Converging Paths of Peace" (Box 7)
  - "Conversations on the Bible" (Box 7)
  - "Converting Our Community" (Box 7)
  - "Conviction of Sin" (Box 7)
  - "Cooperation for Christian Action" (Box 7)
  - "The Coronation of the Risen Christ" (Box 7)
  - "Coronation Without Crucifixion" (Box 7)
  - "Costly Temple Stones" (Box 7)
  - "Could the World End?" (Box 7)
  - "The Country Nobody Knows" (Box 7)
  - "The Country Without a King" (Box 7)
  - "Courage" (Box 7)
  - "Courage For the Bigger Battles" (Box 7)
  - "The Courage of the Christian Witness" (Box 7)
  - "Courtesy to Christ" (Box 7)
  - "The Courteous Congregation" (Box 7)
  - "Creating the Future" (Box 7)
  - "Creation's Dawn" (Box 7)
  - "Creative Resurrection" (Box 7)
  - "Creative Thanksgiving" (Box 7)
  - "The Cross Above the Rain Trees" (Box 7)
  - "Crosses and Crowns" (Box 7)
  - "The Cross and its Resources" (Box 7)
  - "The Cross of Hiroshima" (Box 7)
  - "The Cry of a Lonely Man" (Box 7)
  - "The Cult of the Comfortable" (Box 7)
  - "The Dark Background for a Better Resurrection" (Box 8)
  - "David and His Armor" (Box 8)
  - "The Dawn Patrol" (Box 8)
  - "The Day of Good Tidings" (Box 8)
  - "The Day Without Questions" (Box 8)
  - "Daylight Saving" (Box 8)
  - "The Days Ordained" (Box 8)
  - "The Deacon" (Box 8)
  - "Death" (Box 8)
  - "The Death of Time" (Box 8)
  - Dedication of Missouri's Voting Machines (Box 8)
  - "Deep Sea Fishing" (Box 8)
  - "Deepening the Spiritual Life of Youth" (Box 8)
  - "The Defeat of Fear" (Box 8)
  - "Delayed Answers to Prayer" (Box 8)
  - "Deliverance from Evil" (Box 8)
  - "Delmar's Finest Hour" (Box 8)
  - "The Demonstrable Christ" (Box 8)
  - "Denominational Unrest" (Box 8)
  - "Denominationalism in Modern Christianity" (Box 8)
  - "The D.P.'s-Most Tragic Figures of Our Generation" (Box 8)
  - "Desire of Nations" (Box 8)
  - "The Devils Knew Him" (Box 8)
  - "The Devoted Thing" (Box 8)
  - "The Dignity of Christ" (Box 8)
  - "The Dignity of the Cross" (Box 8)
  - "The Diligent Ruler" (Box 8)
  - "Disciples and Believers" (Box 8)
  - "The Disciples' Fear of the Converted Persecutor" (Box 8)
  - "Disciples of Peace" (Box 8)
  - "The Disciplines of Difficulty" (Box 8)
  - "Discovering the Bible" (Box 8)
  - "Discovering the Savior" (Box 8)
  - "A Disgruntled Preacher" (Box 8)
  - "A Dismembered Civilization in Search of Security" (Box 8)
  - "Divine Thanksgiving Dinner" (Box 8)
  - "Divine Distribution in the Church" (Box 8)
  - "Do They Want a Shepherd?" (Box 8)
  - "Do We Have a Guardian Angel?" (Box 8)
  - "Do You Belong?" (Box 8)
  - "Does the Church Care?" (Box 8)
  - "Dominion Over All" (Box 8)
  - "Doom or Down?" (Box 8)
  - "The Dove and the Fire" (Box 8)
  - "Down to the Sea in Ships" (Box 8)
  - "The Dreams of the. Blind" (Box 8)
  - "Dual Alignment and Eastern Christianity" (Box 8)
  - "The Dungeon of Malchijah" (Box 8)
  - "Dying With Christ" (Box 8)
  - "Eagle's Wings" (Box 8)
  - "Early Church Life in Syracuse" (Box 8)